As you're starting to see,
正如你开始看到的
this config piece is pretty powerful.
这个 config 部分非常强大
And we can use it to modify our entire code base and our entire project
我们可以使用它来修改整个代码库和项目
to give our project more functionality.
从而为我们的项目提供更多的功能
What else can this do?
它还能做些什么？
Well, right now, as you can see, every time we work with a hard hat network, every time we run a script,
正如你看到的，每次我们使用 "Hardhat Network" 运行脚本
we run that script, and then the Hard Hat Network is deleted, right?
运行完之后，那个 "Hardhat Network" 就会被删除，对吧？
We can't interact with our contracts anymore.
这样我们就不能再与我们的合约做进一步的交互了
Well, there's actually a way for us to run
其实有一种方法可以让我们运行一个
a hard hat network. Similar to how we ran a ganache network with a user interface.
类似于使用用户界面运行的 "Ganache Network" 那样的 "Hardhat Network"
What we can do in hard hat is run yarn, RT hat node.
我们可以这样做 "yarn hardhat node"
And what this will do is it'll spin up a node on a local network,
这样做的效果就是在本地网络上启动一个节点
exactly the same as ganache but in our terminal.
并且它与 Ganache 完全相同，只不过是运行于我们的终端里
So you see here started HTTP and WebSocket. JSON RPC server at this address.
所以你可以看到“启动 HTTP 以及 WebSocket JSON-RPC 服务于”，这个地址
And just like nosh, it comes packed with all these different accounts and private keys, which is awesome.
并且和 Ganache 一样，它打包了这么多不同的账户和私钥，真是太好了
You'll notice though, interestingly enough that this node that we're running
你可能会注意到，有趣的是这个节点
isn't on the Hard Hat Network,
并没有运行于 "Hardhat Network"
well, we can actually create a new terminal to try to interact with this
我们可以创建一个新的终端尝试与之交互
just by hitting this little plus button
只要点击这边的这个小加号
and creating a new terminal.
就可以创建一个新的终端
Again, I'm using bash,
再次强调，我正在使用的是 bash
but based off of whatever your operating system is, you can be using a different shell.
但根据你所使用的操作系统，你使用的可能是不同的 shell(命令解释器)
And here, let's go ahead and run yarn arhat run scripts, deploy dot j s, and see what happens.
让我们继续运行 "yarn hardhat run scripts/deploy.js" 看看会发生什么
Well, our typical setup happens, we deploy a contract, we get a contract address, we update the value.
恩，出现了我们的经典结果，我们部署了合约，获取了合约地址，更新了值
But if we look at our node,
但如果查看我们的节点
it doesn't look like any transactions went through what
看起来并没有任何交易发生
we don't see any locking here.
我们在这里没有看到任何日志出现
So what's going on?
所以这是怎么回事？
Well, our Hard Hat Network is actually different from this locally running network here.
我们的 "Hardhat Network" 与这个本地运行的网络其实是不同的
This locally running network we often want to refer to as our local host.
这个本地运行的网络我们通常称之为本地主机(localhost)
So it's slightly different than the Hard Hat Network.
因此它与 "Hardhat Network" 略有不同
It's still using the hard hat runtime environment, but it's just not this default Hard Hat Network.
它仍然在使用 Hardhat 运行环境，只不过不是这个默认的 "Hardhat Network" 了
It's considered its own separate network
它可以被认为是一个独立的网络
when we're running a node hat it's going to live. of past the duration of a script.
并且运行的这个节点会在脚本运行结束之后持续存在
So we can actually interact with this by adding a new network to our hardhead.config.js,
我们可以在 "hardhat.config.js" 中添加一个新的网络来与它进行交互
we'll create a new network and call it local host.
创建一个新的网络并命名为 "localhost"
And exactly as we did up here, we'll give it a URL accounts and a chain ID.
并且就和我们这里做的一样，我们会给它一个 "URL", "accounts" 还有 "chainId"
So for URL, we can get that URL right from our terminal,
对于 "URL"，我们可以从终端获取这个 "URL"
I'll put a running yarn hard hat node.
就是运行 "yarn hardhat node" 的输出
by copying that and pasting it in here,
复制，然后粘贴到这里
we can then do a comma, we'll give it a chain ID of 31337.
接着输入一个逗号，并给它一个 "chainId: 31337"
Because even though it's considered a different network,
因为即使它可以被认为是一个不同的网络
it actually has the same chain ID as hard hat.
它也仍然和 Hardhat 是一样的 "chainId"
Interestingly enough, I know I just said we were going to give it accounts,
有趣的是，虽然我刚刚说了要给它一个 "accounts"
but we actually don't need to give it accounts.
但实际上并不需要
Because when we run with this localhost
因为当我们使用本地主机运行时
hard hat will automatically give us these 10 fake accounts for us.
Hardhat 会自动提供给我们 10 个假账户
So you can kind of think of the accounts here for this localhost as,
所以你可以把这里的 "accounts" 视为本地主机的账户
as hard had already placing them in
因为 Hardhat 已经把它们放进去了
thanks, hard hat.
谢了，Hardhat！
But now, if we go back to our bash here, let's clear the terminal.
但现在，如果我们返回这个 bash 让我们清除这个终端
Let's rerun the script. And we'll do dash dash network local host.
让我们重新运行这个脚本，并且这次加上 "--network localhost"
Now we should be pointing to this node.
现在我们应该就指向这个节点了
And when I run this script, we should see some logging output at the end of this node.
并且当我运行这个脚本时，我们应该就可以在这个节点的末尾看到一些日志输出了
So let's go ahead and hit enter.
让我们继续，按下回车
Well, we see our normal stuff on our deploy script, we flip back to our node
好了，我们看到了一些 "deploy" 脚本的正常输出，回到我们的节点
Wow, we see a ton of logging here.
哇，我们在这里看到了一大堆日志记录
Similar to ganache, we can see a whole bunch of different logs on what just happened,
与 Ganache 相似，我们可以看到一大堆刚刚发生的事的不同日志
we can see a contract was deployed,
我们可以看到部署好的合约
we can see the address the transaction hash from value, gas, and the block number and everything.
还有它的 "address"，"Transaction" 哈希，"From"，"Value"，"Gas"，以及 "Block" 编号和其他的一切
We can also see our contract call calling the store function to update the value of our favorite number.
我们还可以看到我们的合约调用了 "store" 函数更新了 "favoriteNumber" 的值
This is incredibly powerful for quickly testing and working with things on a local JavaScript VM or hard hat network
这对于在本地 "JavaScript VM" 或 "Hardhat Network" 上快速测试和处理事务
to be able to see how your contracts will interact on a real test net.
以及查看你的合约如何与真正的测试网络交互而言，非常强大
And this is much quicker than working with a real test net.
并且这比使用真正的测试网络要快得多
Now additionally, same as what we said before,
另外，就和我之前说的一样
any process that's running in the terminal, we can kill it with Ctrl C.
任何在终端中运行的进程，我们都可以通过 "Ctrl C" 来杀死它
So if you want to stop your node and then restart it,
所以如果你想要停止你的节点并重新启动它的话
you can hit Ctrl. C, to stop it,
你可以按 "Ctrl C" 来停止它
and then just up and then rerun that same command to re spin up your node
然后按上键("↑")再次运行相同的命令来重新启动你的节点
Ctrl C stops it. And then you can up to start again.
"Ctrl C" 停止，接着按 "↑" 键来再次启动
Another way you can stop it, of course,
当然了，还有另一种方法可以终止它
is if you hit the trashcan, which deletes the whole terminal,
如果你点击这个“垃圾桶”，就会删除整个终端
we pulled a terminal back up, we can run it again.
重新拉起一个终端，就可以再次运行了
And just remember, if you hit the X that actually doesn't delete the terminal, that just hides it.
并且要记住，如果你点击的是 "X"，那么它其实并没有删除这个终端，而只是暂时隐藏了
So our hard hat node right now is still running
所以我们的 Hardhat 节点现在仍然在运行中
because I just hit it. So I pull it back up,
因为我只是隐藏了它，把它重新拉起
I can see that it is indeed still running.
就可以看到确实是仍然在运行
But if I trashed candidate, and then it pulled the terminal back up,
但如果我点击的是“垃圾桶”，接着再把终端重新拉起来
I can see that it is no longer running.
就可以看到它已经不再运行了